<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data analytics portfolio on Homepage</title>
    <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data analytics portfolio on Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visualization III : Power supply in India </title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-3/</guid>
      <description>Power supply in India
  The electricity generation target of conventional sources for the year 2021-22 has been fixed as 1356 Billion Units (BU), i.e., growth of around 9.83% over an actual conventional generation of 1234.608 BU for the previous year (2020-21).
  Let&amp;rsquo;s see how the requirements and availability, and distribution of power have changed in India in the last 12 years.
  I have used the data available on the website of Ministry of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization II : Pfizer&#39;s market capitalization </title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-2/</guid>
      <description>Gavi’s COVAX Advance Market Commitment
  On 10 June, 2021 President Joe Biden announced that United States will donate 500 million Pfizer vaccines to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and economies.
  The vaccine maker Pfizer has got the order from the government. The pandemic has been profitable for the pharma sector and Pfizer has also added huge amounts to its valuation.
  It would be interesting to compare the market value of Pfizer with the GDP of countries that will be getting the benefits of free vaccines by U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization I : Fortune 500 </title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/viz-1/</guid>
      <description>The Fortune 500
  When it comes to market capitalization/value the top 4-5 companies on the list of Fortune 500 hold a significant share in the market.
  For studying this I have gathered data from the official website of Fortune.
  After that I have used Power BI for making visualization, that shows the market value of top 25 Fortune 500 companies for 2021.
   Top 25 companies as per market value    From the visualizations we can observe that the top 4 companies Apple, Microsoft, Amazon, Alphabet(Google) have a combined market share of nearly 46% of the total market capitalization of top 25 companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project II: The G.O.A.T keeper debate!</title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>DIFFERENT STYLES OF GOALKEEPING
  I have studied the style of playing of German goalkeeper Manuel Neuer and English goalkeeper Jordan Pickford.
  I have taken the data from their matches in the World cup 2018.
  The visualizations represents the passes(circles) made by these keepers and the direction(arrows) in which these passes were executed.
   Passes made by Jordan Pickford    Passes made by Manuel Neuer   Key observations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Impact of data analytics on FOOTBALL</title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>DATA ANALYTICS IN FOOTBALL
  In this project I&amp;rsquo;m trying to show how data analytics has changed the approach of players in taking attempts on goal.
  This is the &amp;ldquo;expected goals model&amp;rdquo; (a product of data analytics), which essentially tells us what are the probabilities of goal being scored from a certain area on the field.
   The expected goals curve     I have taken data from La Liga season 2006-07 and 2018-19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pa1dayma.github.io/data_analytics_portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Connect with me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pawan--dayma/   Medium: https://pawan-dayma.medium.com/   GitHub: https://github.com/pa1dayma    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
